hello@taverasmisael.com taverasmisael.com @taverasmisael on GitHub

# Misael Taveras

#### **SKILLS**

I'm a developer fascinated with the growing web technologies. I've used *HTML*, *CSS* and *JavaScript* for **over 8 years**. React is the framework that I've worked with the most, but I have experience with **Vue**, **Angular**, and **jQuery**.

I have experience creating documentation and architectures and successfully leading small (1-3 members) teams. I enjoy working on improving testing, documentation, and refactoring, always providing the best service possible. I aim to create responsive and accessible solutions that offer a **top-notch user experience**, no matter how or where the product is accessed.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Virtual Mind, Argentina (remote)** — Senior React Developer

September 2022 - May 2023

- Start the migration of our code from JavaScript to TypeScript.
- Work on the designer tool used by our clients to compose Al views and flows.
- Use React to create new nodes and links representing new states and prompts in the data flow.
- Help with the DTMF responses and configuration.
- Work implementing Microfrontend architecture

#### 'Nuffsaid, Palo Alto(remote) — Senior Frontend Engineer

October 2021 - March 2022

- Work closely implementing our flagship product, focusing on our Messaging editor and interactions.
- Create strategies and plans to develop new features while maintaining existing work.
- Guide and help junior engineers by assigning and monitoring tasks while providing a safe space to grow and experiment.
- Coordinate with the product and engineering team on projects for the following quarters.

## **Virtual Mind, Argentina (remote)** — Senior React Developer

November 2020 - January 2022

- Work multi-project with the integration team to satisfy our client's needs in a CRM-hub app.
- Create strategies to migrate our test and lay the foundation for future testing strategies.
- Continue the migration of our code from Flow to TypeScript.
- Implement new features across different teams and repos.
- Interview candidates for Senior and Mid Engineering positions.

## **Avantica Technologies, Costa Rica (remote)** — Senior React Developer

August 2019 - August 2020

- Maintain legacy Backbone.js code while implementing new features using React.
- Do architecture for testing our four different apps (frontend)
- Migrate legacy Ruby, jQuery and Backbone code to React.
- Expand our proprietary React components library.

#### **GBH, Dominican Republic**— Senior Developer

January 2018 - September 2019

- Led a small team of devs to develop our client vision
- Work refactoring a whole React and Python application. Add tests to the app mentioned above.
- Do the whole architecture for the new App using React, redux and jest tests.
- Create a component library to share between our two apps.
- Work on a couple of features in the React Native iOS app.

#### **GBH**, **Dominican Republic**— Senior Frontend Developer

April 2018 - January 2019

- Create tailored websites for our clients using WordPress
- Use jQuery and VUE.js to create features and pages for our client's websites.
- Develop a customisable template for a real estate broker's company, making it
  easier for the representatives to have personal websites connected to the real
  estate API but keeping in touch with the overall brand.

#### **Viral Reach, Dominican Republic**— Frontend Developer

April 2017 - January 2018

- Create tailored websites for our clients using WordPress
- Use jQuery and VUE.js to create features and pages for our client's websites.
- Develop a customisable template for a real estate broker's company, making it
  easier for the representatives to have personal websites connected to the real
  estate API but keeping in touch with the overall brand.

# **Rosmir Group, Dominican Republic**— Frontend Developer (Freelancer)

March 2016 - Oct 2018

- Create tools to integrate clients' internal services with their websites using Node.js.
- Create tailored websites for our clients using WordPress.
- Work on Regresan.do a survey platform for restaurants and pharmacies.
- Work on RegresanDO's dashboard to present the collected data to our clients so they can improve their services.

#### **University O&M, Dominican Republic**— Web Developer

Jan 2016 - Jun 2017

- Create a new portal for our university.
- Create websites using only HTML, SASS and JavaScript.
- Create the university's official blog using WordPress.
- Provide support and develop features for the university's administration app.

# **EDUCATION**

**University O&M, Dominican Republic** — Computer Science BE.

January 2012 - 2017

**Carnegie Mellon University, Pennsylvania (online)** — *Software Architecture Principles and Practices* 

November 2018 - January 2019